Assalamu alaikum, Muhammad! I am here for the Telegram application lessons.
...will be released. In the previous lesson, we looked at its source code. Telegram's source code,
its library and the integration of its files. We enabled it on the GitHub project.
We had set it up. But we saw that in the previous lesson.
Today, we will look at how to handle the authorization fields for Telegram in the UI.
We will see what we did last time. We had an existing file that...
I don't know, I just created it structured...
...with the Developer and Tester roles, organizing it into **Domain**, **Infrastructure**,
and **Presentation** layers, and I just opened it up here.
Because this uses the main functions of Telegram and then, for the Flutter presentation, Flutter is...
...used. I opened a folder called **Constant** inside **Domain**, and inside that,
I opened a file called **Credentials**.
I opened an object. Inside this object,
the Telegram credentials will be placed: Your **API ID**, **API hash**, and **database**
**encryption key**. The database encryption key is something you can generate yourself, it
should be auto-generated, and you might want to save it somewhere.
You need the **API ID** and **API hash** from Telegram, and you need to save them.
To get these, you need to go to the **Create Telegram Application** page.
You go to **Create your Telegram Application** and click the link. This is a very
detailed explanation of these steps.
You go into **API development**, and you'll need your phone number. You
create an application, and the created application will show you your credentials.
You fill in those details: the **API ID** and **API hash** that you wrote down.
You put it there. I think that's clear.
I will put the image here as a placeholder. But I will cover the image so it's clear.
Done, we have prepared this. Now we go back to the service.
The service is waiting here, and we will write in the service of this task...
...to Telegram, whether it's a notification, or getting channels, or our chats.
We will do everything. To do this, we need a Client in Telegram. A Client that calls, a Client that calls...
We need our own... Oh, a Client, that's what it is called, a Client that calls,
it's called a Client in my case. Oh, this one is from my structure.
Okay, we can save this structured **Client** as our own **Client**.
Okay, let's call it **TdClient** for short. What's next?
The next one is the **Telegram Client**, the **Telegram API**.
This service probably uses the Telegram database, and we'll have to deal with the package.
...for this class. You can watch the previous video. We need to open a **Telegram Client**.
We open it here. We take the credentials from the other file, for a quiet...
...maybe Telegram Flutter Telegram **Credentials**, **Credentials**.
Telegram Credentials. Okay. Next is our **late final**...
Is that the correct keyword?
Yes, I think so.
Oh, **initialization**. We'll leave it for now. I don't know why this code
changed. Let's show the samples. **API ID**. Let's make it **final**...
...first **String**.
**API ID** should be an **int**.
**API hash** should be a **String**. **API hash** is what I showed.
Next is **final late final String db.encryptionKey**. We need this for initialization, to always initialize...
We need this for initialization, to always initialize...
We need a **static late final int**...
...an **int** called **myUserId**. This user ID, from the Telegram user file,
is needed for many things, so I made it a global variable here.
I'm thinking this will optimize the code later, so let's leave it for now.
What else do we need? We will call the client from TdLib. The client calls TdLib.
...the client from TdLib.
...that client. We will save it as a **Client**. This **Client** is for when we...
...log in to our device. This is its **Instance**. Okay, let's leave it.
And what comes after this?
After this, for a static change, we'll create a **singleton**.
It will be initialized once, and the one that is placed will always run.
Here we open an **Instance**.
Now, I'll open a Telegram constructor.
The default constructor. I'll open a **private constructor**
and close the braces.
We select the **API hash** and everything inside this, but the importance is that it comes from **Credentials**.
The reason it didn't work... Let's check the reason why it didn't work. We need it to be static,
we take it from static, here we go.
Because the instance is created there. There are two other ways, that's fine.
We put this one in the constructor for now. **Credentials.apiId** is here.
The **API ID** is here. For now, it was fine, it won't be initialized again.
Now for this, to avoid confusion, we open a question mark and I know **TelegramClient**, inside this,
we check if the **instance** is null, and if the instance has not been initialized here,
for that, we initialize it again.
We initialize it with **TelegramClient**.
This is our private constructor.
What does the constructor return to us?
It returns this, assigning it to its variables.
Okay, now it's finally initialized and we **return** the **instance**.
That's it. But it didn't take anything.
**Telegram client can't be returned**. We messed up, we'll leave the nullability.
Okay, we left the nullability. This one is strong, maybe this one...
Ah, we need to force it, okay. Okay, after that, this one will be set after our
thought. Everything is ready. We have our credentials. The API is for
giving the information, and the server communicates with it. We have the most important part.
Now we need to figure out what happens when we log into Telegram. For example,
there will be a **homepage**, maybe later, or what happens when authorization is finished.
...We need a primary method.
We'll put a comment. It will be a `Future`
called **initialize**. The purpose of initialize is to check if it's already logged in,
or not to lose the authorization.
It takes **BuildContext** and is **async**.
We use a **try-catch**. Inside, an **if** statement: if the **client** is null,
we create the client again. **client.create** is a method of the library that creates the client instance.
...the method of the library, **Create**.
Next, we use **await** and call **client.initialize**. We initialize it because if it's null, it won't be initialized,
so first we create its object,
and then we initialize it. Okay, after that, we have a method called **listenForUpdates**.
We call this method. This one is like a...
This one uses the **Telegram stream**.
It's a streamable platform. You are logged in from a device,
or you logged out from this platform.
It works in real-time in Telegram.
It doesn't send a GET request and wait for a response.
It works in real-time in Telegram. So, we're done. We call a method. You
need to go to the **login page** if you're trying to log in.
When you enter the SMS, it should show you a prompt.
We only have the authorization related method here now.
You enter your phone number, and it sends you an SMS.
...for the SMS, we call it **Authorization Updates**. It notifies you when your authorization number is entered.
It takes a **BuildContext** because from here we will manage the pages.
Because from here we will manage the pages. Which page should be waited for?
So, we call **client**.
**client.updates**. This is an update stream inside the client. It checks if the client is initialized,
or if a message came to you, or if there's an update.
Everything is here. It's a notification stream in Telegram. We used **listen**.
**Listen** is what waits and looks for things. There are **events** inside, and we can sort them by **event type**.
...sort them by **event type**.
**EventType** is what's used. We do **event.toJson**.
The **type** is inside the JSON.
There are types like this in Telegram. This tells you **ok**, or what step it is.
...what step it is.
We get the **type**.
The **type** is...
Okay, the event's type.
For example, **WaitingCode**, **WaitingConfirmationCode**.
This means you have entered your phone number into Telegram, and it's waiting for you to enter the SMS code.
That's one state.
**WaitingPhoneNumber** means it's waiting for you to enter the phone number. That's one state.
That's one state. We will manage this.
Now, we check: if the **Event type** is
**updateAuthorizationState**. The **authorization state** is what we always
want to set. It's better to use a class here because if there's a syntax
error, it's easier to handle. If the **event type** is
**updateAuthorizationState**, then something will happen.
This means we call the **updateAuthorizationState** class from the **TdLib database API**.
We call the class. The update is the event that came, cast as
**Td.AuthorizationUpdateAuthorizationState**.
We force the update to be non-null to always get a value.
Now we have **Td.AuthorizationState**... the update's authorization state.
...the update's authorization state.
Okay. Now we open another method called **onAuthChanged**. We'll call it that for now, but we'll change the name later.
We'll add more to the parameters. We'll call it **onAuthStateUpdated**.
This method will take the **AuthorizationState**. The **AuthorizationState** is what we got from watching the updates.
It's an **AuthorizationState**. This is what we will use to manage the UI. This is a very useful method.
We open a **switch-case** statement. This is what we'll use to manage the UI.
We open a **switch-case** statement.
...because it's the only one that works. Only the Telegram database gives us the correct state.
It won't give an error. If it does, we'll deal with it then.
Let's show it to our friends. OK.
The first method is **Initialize**. The **Client** is being initialized. The second method is to listen for updates.
Which state are you in? Should I show the phone number? Should I wait for the code?
Should I show the two-factor password? Should I show the homepage? It controls everything,
and it gives you the authorization state. For a mobile application, when you want to switch from one state to another,
when you want to log in, when you want to navigate to the homepage,
this method will help you. Now we will write inside this method.
We need the **AuthorizationState**. It takes **BuildContext** because through this **BuildContext**
we manage the UI. Now I won't manage it, but later I will.
We use **tdc.client** that came here. This is the main function that
will give us the result. The method will be called **switchCase**.
We'll use a **switch-case** statement. This is what we'll use to check the state. The code will only run
if it's logging in. This is how we do it: **switch(AuthorizationState.getConstructor())**.
...**switch(AuthorizationState.getConstructor())**.
**getConstructor** is what gives you the information.
**AuthorizationState** is the current user's state, what state they are in:
logged in, maybe signed up, or something else. We'll see.
It shows those things. So, we'll use a **case** statement:
**tda.authorizationState.waitPhoneNumber**. **WaitPhoneNumber**
means that Telegram is currently waiting for us to enter our phone number to log in.
That's a state.
We need to do something for that.
We need to write a line of code, like **await**...
This uses an **async** method.
**setTdlibParameters**. Do we need to set the parameters here?
No, we'll navigate to another page. If it's waiting for the phone number, then
then it's an **async** call.
future
**navigator.push**
**MaterialPageRoute**, the context, you're going to another page, we'll call that page
**AuthPage**. No, we'll call it **PhoneNumberPage**.
...**PhoneNumberPage**.
**PhonePage**. We need to navigate there. Everything is understood.
It will send you to the **Authorization Page** because you're not logged in.
...It will send you to the **Authorization Page**. You can pass this string to the constructor.
We will pass its constructor. If it's free, it will navigate to the next page.
Now before that, I need to check one more thing.
I'll put a **case** statement here: **case td.authorizationState.waitToDeleteParameter**.
...**waitToDeleteParameter**.
What does this return?
...
If it's **Ready**, ready, then we'll accept the **homepage**.
Done, when we log in again...
...it's the **homepage** because we are authorized.
Our **homepage** might be Telegram...
...with a sidebar.
**Icons.menu**
```