Assalamu alaikum, today we will start the integration of Telegram's TDLib database into Flutter.
This includes the official one, TDLib, Kalibrium, Telegram's...
...official alternative options. TDLib, the other developers' plus Kalibrium.
All of these use Flutter's database.
Now, flat doesn't work, we'll use Telegram's database files. Telegram's...
...is open source, so we can use their files.
We need the necessary tools first. There are 3-4 links, all of them...
...will be below the video, I'll show them.
First, we start by getting the Telegram **API ID** and **App ID** from **my.telegram.org**.
Log into your account, then go to the necessary steps for development.
You enter your phone number. After you've entered it, it will ask for a code. That code...
...will be sent to you. You enter the code that came to you. There are two steps.
The first time you enter, you just log into your account. The next one is...
...creating an application. It asks for a code again. Okay, it's not difficult, friends.
Okay, let's look at the page. You will see something like "**Create your application**".
What do you write on the page? You write the **App Title**. For example, you write its name...
...for what it is. You write the name. Flutter, Telegram, I don't know.
**Short name**, **URL** are not mandatory.
You write the **Short name** and **URL**.
You write the name. For Android, you might choose an appropriate package name now...
...and later a **Description**. This **Application** is essentially...
...what you write about the application.
Then you click **Create Application**, and you're done.
I won't create it now because later it will be... I will have to delete the IDs...
...which might be difficult. I might have to go through a lot to delete them...
...or remove them. It's not difficult, you can create it yourself.
After you create it, it will show you your **API ID** and **API Hash**...
...these credentials.
Take them and save them somewhere for the next step, which I will show you.
Next up, we need to download the whole **TDLib**. Next, we look at the link.
This link is for Telegram's database, and where Telegram's new features...
...new features, new functions are added and released.
Let's look at the page. For Windows and MacOS... I will create a Telegram application for Windows and MacOS...
...on this platform soon.
I won't look at the latest Android version now. I'll look at the Android...
...version around the middle.
You download the whole **zip** file. Okay, it didn't log me in yet.
Here.
It's logged in. After logging in, you click on **Libs**. You download those **Libs**.
Download them. Here, we've downloaded it. Now...
After we've downloaded it, everything is in a folder. I've measured the time.
I'll open the zip file that I downloaded earlier.
Inside, we see a folder called **libs**. We need to put those **libs** into our project...
...in the correct place.
We put those **libs** into our project. The project name doesn't matter.
You will create a project there using **flutter create**.
You have a **Flutter Create** project. You go into that project.
When you look, the folder that opens is the **Android** folder.
Inside the **Android** folder, we look for the **app** folder.
Inside the **app** folder, we look for **src** (**source**). Inside **src**, we see the **main** folder.
Now we copy the **libs** that we downloaded and put them into the **main** folder.
Let's see, it's there. Now we'll open it from **VS Code** and continue.
When we open it from **VS Code**, we go into the **android** folder, then the **app** folder, then the **src** folder.
Here we have the **Libs** folder. Now we need to correctly add it...
...put it in, and configure it.
For this, let's look at the **app** folder. Inside the **app** folder, we go to **build.gradle**.
We need to find the **SourceSets** block.
That **SourceSet**...
...then we name it **libs** below.
`libs.sourceDirectories` is what's used for this purpose.
We put it as `source`.
The syntax shouldn't have an error. So we set it as `source.main.libs`.
Look, this **libs** is related to the name.
If your folder is named something else, you need to use that name here.
Okay.
I've said the necessary things about the version. Okay, now for the next step.
We've done everything. Now we need to connect to your repository.
Your repository is on **GitHub**, and the link will be under the video.
Go there. When we go for the machine, we'll see that...
We see the package, I'll copy it. I copy it and go into **pubspec.yaml**...
...of our project. We go into **pubspec.yaml** and open it like this.
You copy and paste it into the code. I'll just write it for now for time...
...reasons. You'll see the same thing. You copy that.
You write it as **tdlib**. You give the URL of the **Git** repository.
You give the URL that you got from **Git** and set the reference to **master**.
That is, this is **main**, we know it's from the first one.
It's from **master**. We'll stop at this point. The first step is complete.
That is, the integration part is complete.
Now we'll only start coding.
```